我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
but secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
我让杀害母亲的凶手自食其果
I hunted down the man who killed my mother,
但我们的世界也因此出现了新的威胁
but in doing so, I opened up our world to new threats,
我是唯一来得及阻止他们的人
and I am the only one fast enough to stop them.
我叫闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
爱瑞丝的妈妈还活着
Iris's mom is alive.
你觉得你可以给我钱
And you thought you could pay me
让我离开我女儿吗
to walk away from my own daughter.
上一次  你一毛钱没得就离开了
Last time you walked away for free.
当你制造了奇点
When you created the singularity,
你也制造了一个缺口
you also created a breach--
连接两个世界的传送门
a portal connecting our two earths.
你真认为他只是叫这些人来杀我吗
You really think he's just bringing these guys here to kill me?
极速一心想要消灭我
Zoom is obsessed with destroying me.
现在他想消灭你
Now he wants to destroy you.
我可以感知到事物  可怕的事情
I'm starting to perceive things--horrible things.
我们得通过黑洞中心分离
We have to merge the inner
融合内外视界
and outer event horizons by separating in the eye of it.
不
No!
罗尼为救我牺牲了  我很抱歉
Ronnie died saving me, and I'm so sorry.
不不不  别过去
No, no, no, get back. Come here.
听得到吗  斯泰因教授
Professor Stein, can you hear me?
两年前
每个人都以为
Everyone secretly thinks
自己知道生活会是什么样
they've figured out what their life is gonna be like,
但没人真正想过  生活为你制定了计划
but what no one ever considers is that life has its own plans for you,
不管你喜欢与否
whether you like them or not.
所以你要做出选择
And so you're left with a choice.
要么接受改变  继续前行
You can either embrace the change and move forward,
猎鹰队
要么与之抗衡  被生活遗弃
or fight it, and be left behind.
伙计  我就知道你可以的
Dude! I knew you could do it.
触地得分啊伙计  我们能赢  都是你的功劳
That was some touchdown, man. You won us the game!
不  伙计  是大家的功劳
Hey, no, man. We won us the game.
拉拉队的人可不是这么说的
Hey, that's not what the cheerleaders were saying.
是吗  讲真吗  好吧
Oh, yeah? For real? A'ight.
杰佛逊  比赛很精彩
Jefferson, great game.
谢谢  教练
Hey, thanks, coach.
我不是唯一一个注意到的人
I'm not the only one that noticed.
你那次触地得分后
Lot of scouts in the stands tonight,
今晚很多的观察员
and after that touchdown,
都掏出了手机
they all pulled out their cell phones.
会有很多大学争著录取你  孩子
You're gonna get your pick of colleges, son.
真的吗
You really think so?
我确定
I know so.
回家和你妈妈庆祝一下吧
You get home and celebrate with your mom.
大家快跑
Everybody, run!
快站起来伙计  我扶着你
Hey, hey, come on, man, I got you!
我们得进隧道
We gotta get inside the tunnel!
猎鹰队
抓紧他
Hold him steady!
他要不行了
He's dropping out.
不要  不要  不要
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
西斯科  我们要失去他了
Cisco, we're losing him!
我来
Got it!
天啊  感谢上苍
Oh, Dios mio. Thank God.
他的情况越来越糟了
He's getting worse.
我已经尽全力重新设计
Look, I did what I could to re-engineer
威尔斯博士的稳定装置  来抑制不良反应
Doctor Wells's original stabilizer to quell the reaction,
但我不知道他的能量源是什么
but I don't know what he used as a power source.
我能找到的最好的能量源  就是他轮椅里那个
Best I could find was the one from his wheelchair.
那个能撑多久
And how long will that last?
问题就在这里  在追天气巫师
Well, that's the problem, is we had already used up
及其同伙的那次空中之旅
most of its energy trying to dampen the metas' powers
我们为了抑制转化人的能力  能量用的差不多了
during our little rogue air trip with Weather Wizard and company.
最多能撑两三天
I think we got a few days tops.
他只能躺床上吗
And he's stuck in bed?
对  他一旦醒过来
Yeah, when he wakes up,
我就把稳定装置转接到这里
I'm gonna transfer the stabilizer to this,
给他提供动力  让他走动
give him a power cane, get him moving.
我们得想办法救他
We gotta figure out a way to save him.
我想我可能知道该怎么做
I think I might know how to do that.
粒子加速器爆炸时
When the Particle Accelerator exploded,
冲击斯泰因教授的暗物质
the dark matter that collided with Professor Stein
和火风暴模型融合在了一起
fused with the Firestorm matrix
改变了他体内的分子过程
and altered the normal molecular processes that occurs within his body.
那些高分应分子
Those highly reactive molecules
需要结合其他物质才能稳定
needed something to bond with in order to stabilize.
所以就和罗尼融合了
And that's where Ronnie came in.
对  既然罗尼已经不再是
Yes, and now that Ronnie is no longer
斯坦因教授体内的一部分
a part of Professor Stein--
这些分子就没有东西结合
Those molecules don't have anything to bond to.
他在非融合状态的时间越久
And the longer he goes without merging,
就会越不稳定
the more unstable he becomes.
好  那我们该怎么做
All right, so, what do we do?
我们再找一个...参与者
We find another... participant.
酷  那  怎么找呢
Okay, cool, so, how do we do that?
开发一个名叫"火种"的应用程序  寻找潜在转化人吗
Are we just gonna make a Tinder app for potential meta-humans?
因为跟斯坦因教授融合  时不时迸出火焰
'Cause I'm pretty sure merging with Stein and randomly bursting into flames
听上去真的是史上最无吸引力之事
sounds like the biggest "Swipe left" of all time.
即使我们真能找到愿意的人
I mean, even if we could find someone willing,
斯坦因也不是想跟谁融合就能融合的吧
Stein can't just merge with whoever he wants.
确实不是  但我做了些研究
No he can't, but I have done some research,
找到两个候选人
and found two potential candidates
这两个人跟教授可以兼容
that might be compatible with him.
他们都被暗物质影响了
They both were affected by the dark matter,
医院也承认他们有
and they were both admitted to the hospital
基因重组突变的症状
showing symptoms of gene rearrangement mutation.
亨利·翰威特
杰佛逊·杰克逊
而且他们俩的血型跟斯坦因教授和罗尼都一样
And they both share the same blood type as Professor Stein and Ronnie.
好吧
All right.
我是说  这可不比器官捐献
I mean, this is more than organ donation.
我们也不能单靠组织分型
We'll need more than tissue typing
来判断他们和教授能否兼容
to see if their bodies are compatible.
如果我可以分离这两人的基因位点
If I can isolate the genetic locus of the two candidates
和斯坦因教授的突变基因做交叉比对
and cross-reference it with the mutations in Professor Stein,
或许能找到匹配的人选  就可以救他了
I might be able to find a match and save his life.
你需要什么
What do you need to do that?
到手了  两个候选人的血样
All right, blood samples from both potential candidates.
虽然你是闪电侠  但这也太快了吧
Damn, that was fast even for you.
我可能跳过了征求意见这个环节
I may have skipped the asking for permission part.
我们看看能不能找到匹配人选吧
Let's see if we can't find a match.
照片里你是两岁吧
You were two in that picture.
被打了几针  你就对护士非常恼怒
You'd just got some shots. You were so mad at the nurse.
你不停地说  "她弄痛我了"
You kept saying, "She pinched me."
所有我们就带你去公园  逗你开心
So we took you to the park afterwards to cheer you up,
给你买了人生第一支冰淇淋甜筒
gave you your first ice cream cone,
真是个错误  因为接下来一个月你整天重复一句话
which was a mistake, because all we heard the next month was,
"巧克力薄荷  巧克力薄荷"
"Mint-choplat chip, mint-choplat chip."
原来就是从那时候爱上吃这个的
That's where the obsession started.
宝贝  你不必去见她
Babe, you don't have to do this.
如果明天你不想见你母亲  我能理解
If you don't want to meet your mother tomorrow, I get it.
不 没关系  我想见她
No, it's okay. I want to meet her.
我需要见她一面
I need to meet her.
不会有事的
It's gonna be fine.
我宝贝女儿真勇敢
My brave baby girl.
遗传的你
Take after you.
我爱你
Love you.
我更爱你
Love you more.
中城警察局
巴里
Barry?
我正找你呢
Hey, I was just looking for you.
我该打电话的  但我还没有你的电话号码
I would've called, but I don't have your number yet, so.
哦对...
Oh, yeah--
不不不  我只是想给你看这个
No, no, no, I just wanted to show you this.
是刚找到的资料
These were just found
在伊斯特伍德大道的一个小巷里
in an alley off of Eastwood Avenue.
这些是什么  牙齿吗
What are these, teeth?
鲨鱼牙齿
Shark teeth.
而且我还有个目击证人说
And I have an eyewitness that says
他看到鲨鱼在地上走  一个人形鲨鱼
he saw a shark walking on land--a man-shark.
-人形鲨鱼  -没错
- Man-shark? - Yeah.
听起来像是科幻烂片里的
Sounds like a bad sci-fi movie.
或者是科幻神作
Or awesome sci-fi movie.
没错
Totally.
你是认真的吗  你真的认为有那么个...
Are you for real? You think there's actually, ke, a shark--
是啊  我知道这听起来很诡异...
Yeah, I mean, I know it sounds really wacko...
但是  现在也没有什么是不太可能的了
But, I mean, nothing seems impossible now that
我们都有超能力者了  不是吗
we have meta-humans, right?
而且我觉得肯定很有意思  你知道
And I thought it would be fun, you know,
咱俩又在一起办案子什么的
for us to work together again on a case.
好吧  我是真的
Yeah, I mean, I really--
挺像和你在一起做各种事的
I'd love to work on anything with you.
但是  只不过
Um, it's just, you know,
对付超能力者不是我的强项
meta-humans aren't really my thing.
哦好吧  没关系  我自己能处理
Oh, okay, yeah, that's fine. I can handle it.
不用  你  要么我就...
No, you--look, how about I just--
我帮你做个测试  看看牙齿是哪来的
I'll run a test, see where the teeth came from.
那真是太好了
That would be amazing.
-那好吧  -谢了
- All right, cool. - Thanks.
没关系
Yeah, sure.
斯皮沃特警探
Detective Spivot.
警探
Detective.
你那个人形鲨鱼的案子怎么样了
How's your man-shark case coming?
挺顺利的  我正要去一趟现场
It's good. I was just gonna go
四处搜查一下  看看能找到什么线索
and canvas the area, see what else I can dig up,
而且巴里也刚答应帮我做一些测试
and Barry here agreed to run some tests for me.
真的吗
Really?
所以  有进展  再次感谢
So, progress. Thanks again.
如果我不是知道内情
If I don't know any better,
我会以为你在和我搭档调情
I'd say you were flirting with my partner.
什么  帕蒂  没有...
What, Patty? No, I'm--
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我没有
I'm not--
你和爱瑞丝还有我搭档这是什么剧情
What is it with you and Iris and my partners?
话说爱瑞丝怎么样了
Hey, how is Iris, by the way?
她挺紧张的
Eh, she's pretty nervous
时隔这么多年后与母亲重聚
about seeing her mother after all these years.
是啊
Yeah.
话说  我得走了
Hey, you know what, I gotta go.
是西斯科  关于斯坦因教授的事
It's Cisco. It's about Professor Stein.
好的  去吧  辛格这边我给你打掩护
Okay, go. I'll cover you with Singh.
那好  谢了
All right, thanks.
我必须承认  我从没想到过
Well, I must admit, I never imagined
斯芬克斯那关于人类要三条腿的谜题
the Sphinx's riddle about a man requiring three legs
能够发生在我身上
would ever apply to me,
但如果这装置能让我自由移动
but if this device keeps me mobile,
那我也就只能虚心接受了
then I will gratefully oblige.
幸运的是  你不需要用这东西太久
Hopefully, you won't need it for much longer.
血液样本中没有凝集反应
There was no agglutination in the blood samples,
亨利·翰威特
而交叉配型后  两者都显阴性
and cross-matching was negative for both,
看起来那来自于
and it appears that the dark matter
粒子加速器爆炸的暗物质
from the Particle Accelerator explosion
以和你情况一样的方式变异了他们的基因
mutated their genes in a very similar way it did to yours.
我想他们都是潜在的匹配者
I think they're both potential matches.
那么我们要选谁
So who do we go with?
我的首选是亨利·翰威特
Well, my first choice is Henry Hewitt.
“火风暴漫画中的对手之一”
他以最优异的成绩毕业于哈德森学院
He graduated summa cum laude from Hudson University
获得了应用物理与生物工程双学位
with a double major in Applied Physics and Bioengineering.
哈德森的孩子  我已经喜欢上他了
A Hudson boy, I like him already.
那另一个杰佛逊·杰克逊怎么样
Now, what about this other guy Jefferson Jackson?
“漫画中"火风暴"罗尼·雷蒙德的朋友”
高中橄榄球队四分卫  全优学生
High school quarterback, 4.0 student.
他身体素质不错
He's got the physical attributes.
杰佛逊·杰克逊
而且看起来他的等位基因比翰威特更匹配
And it looks like more of his alleles match than Hewitt's.
这不就是说他更加合适吗
Doesn't that mean that he's more compatible?
纸上看也许是  但翰威特是科学家
On paper, perhaps, but Hewitt is a scientist.
显然  他想要做出一番事业
Clearly, he's trying to make something of his life.
我觉得他会对这种事更感兴趣
I think he'd be open to something like this.
我觉得我们在决定前应该两个都见见
I think we should meet with both of them before we make a decision.
这个想法很棒
That's an excellent idea.
我去看能不能把翰威特找来
I'll see if I can get Hewitt here.
与此同时  我们去见杰佛逊·杰克逊
All right, in the meantime, we'll go meet with Jefferson Jackson.
而我会找找看有没有办法
And I will try to find something else
让你更稳定一些
to help keep you stable.
你觉得咱们找对地方了吗
Are you sure this is the right place?
没错  杰佛逊是个机修工
Yeah. Jefferson's a mechanic.
可能会带来不小的技工能力
Could indicate a strong technical aptitude.
这是个优势
That's a positive.
容易过敏
Oh, prone to allergies.
这就绝对是缺点了
That's definitely a negative,
更别提他听音乐的品味了
not to mention his taste in music.
你是不是更喜欢听席琳·狄翁的
Would you prefer Celine Dion instead?
我这里有《泰坦尼克号》的原声
I got the "Titanic" Soundtrack in the back there.
不用了  谢谢
No, thank you.
杰佛逊·杰克逊  对吗
Jefferson Jackson, right?
大家都加我杰克斯
People call me Jax.
朗朗上口
Ooh, catchy.
我名叫巴里·艾伦  这是马丁·斯泰因
My name's Barry Allen, and this is Martin Stein.
我们是安全部门的
We're with the Department of Safety.
是个挺小的新部门
It's a small, newly formed agency.
非常的新  好像网站都没有呢  是吧
Very new, we probably don't even have a website yet, do we?
你要看我们的营业执照吗
You need to see our licenses?
我是说  我们这里很正规的
I mean, we're all up to code here.
不不  不是那回事
No, no, nothing like that.
我们在为两年前受到
We are compiling data on people who were affected
粒子加速器爆炸影响的人进行编制资料
by the Particle Accelerator explosion two years ago.
老兄  我为那出问题的蠢东西
Look, man, I lost enough time in my life
已经浪费了够多的人生
'cause of that stupid thing going wrong.
如果你不需要我修车  那我就没法帮你了
Now, you don't got a car I can fix, I can't help you.
如果你可以和我们回尖端科研实验室
If you would consider coming back to S.T.A.R. Labs with us,
我想我们可以帮助你
I believe we can help you.
怎么帮我
Help me how?
我们知道粒子加速器的影响...
Well, we know what the Particle Accelerator did--
我跟你说了  我不想谈那晚的事
Look, I already told you, I don't talk about that night.
为什么
Why is that?
因为从那时起一切都变了
Because that's when everything changed.
我受到了重创
I got hit hard.
当我醒来时  我在医院里
When I woke up, I was in the hospital.
腿部受伤  韧带撕裂
Busted up leg, torn ACL.
看到我妈妈脸上那表情
The look on my mom's face,
我就知道我的职业橄榄球梦破灭了
I knew any dreams I had of playing pro ball were over.
我为此感到惋惜
I'm sorry to hear that.
是啊
Yeah, well...
我得回去工作了
Look, I gotta get back to work.
好吧
Yeah, um...
给你  这个是...
Here, it's just...
是我们的电话
it's our number.
考虑一下  好吗
Just think about it, okay?
谢谢你帮我促和这件事  约瑟夫
Thank you for putting this together, Joseph.
爱瑞丝的主意  不是我的
Iris's idea, not mine.
宝贝
Hey, baby.
爸爸
Hi, Dad.
爱瑞丝  这是弗朗辛
Iris... this is Francine.
你好
Hello.
你好  艾瑞丝
Hi. Hello, Iris.
需要我给你点杯咖啡什么的吗
Can I get you a coffee or something?
不用了  谢谢
Um, no, thanks.
咱们坐下说吧
Let's just sit.
我无法想像你已经这么亭亭玉立了
I can't get over what a beautiful young woman you've become.
还是个记者  我真为你感到骄傲
And a journalist? I'm so proud of you.
你为什么来这里
Why are you here?
为什么是现在  二十年后
Why now, after two decades?
我想弥补之前的错事
I want to make this right with you.
那么不如先从为抛弃我们而道歉开始
How about you start by apologizing for walking out on us?
我很抱歉  真的真的非常抱歉
I am sorry, so very, very sorry.
这里有太多事你不知道
There's so much you don't know.
我相信你一定经历了很多
I'm sure that you've been through a great deal,
我也很感激你
and I can appreciate you feeling like this is
突然觉得现在是时候跟我相认了
suddenly the right time for you to want me in your life,
但我不觉得现在是时候
but that doesn't mean that it's the right time for me.
爱瑞丝
Iris...
没事的  爸爸
No, Dad, it's okay.
我想了很久
I've thought about this a lot,
把这些错算到你的头上不公平
and it wasn't fair for me to make you the bad guy.
所以我想亲自跟你说清楚
So I want you to hear this from me.
我不恨你  弗朗辛
I don't hate you, Francine.
我是真的希望你过得好
I do wish you well,
可是我们都分开生活了20多年
but we have lived separate lives for over 20 years.
就继续这样下去吧
Let's keep it that way.
我一直觉得
I've always thought
我生来应该做些更伟大的事
my destiny was for greater things.
变成更伟大的人
And people, of course.
等我们成功之后
Well, when it's all said and done,
飞行会是你众多超能力中最普通的一种
flying will be the least impressive of your new abilities.
人类终于实现了原子时代的梦想
Man finally achieves the promise of the Atomic Age.
凯特琳  发生了什么
Caitlin, what's going on?
你来得正好  这是亨利·翰威特博士
Hi, I'm glad you're back. This is Dr. Henry Hewitt.
这是巴里·艾伦和马丁·斯泰因博士
This is Barry Allen and Professor Martin Stein.
你好
How do you do?
传说中的马丁·斯泰因
The illustrious Martin Stein.
我在哈德森读了你所有的文章
I've read all your papers back at Hudson,
尤其是有关转化的  写得太好了
especially on transmutation. Fascinating.
-你就是个学术传说  -你过奖了
- You're a legend. - Oh, please.
我没你说的那么厉害
I think you're overestimating my contribution to the field.
-我很高兴你有这种积极性  -他难道不好吗
- I—I appreciate your enthusiasm. - Isn't he great?
他的野心就跟德克萨斯一样大
He's got an ego the size of Texas,
不过也就还好了
but, yeah, he's all right.
说起来  杰佛逊·杰克逊呢
So, where's Jefferson Jackson?
还需要点时间说服他
We just need more time.
我们没时间了
We don't have more time.
我没法给拐杖
I couldn't find another power source
再找一个能量源  现在这个也快没电了
for the cane and that thing's running out.
那就合体吧  翰威特同意了
Okay, then let's do the merge. Hewitt's in.
什么意思  你把火风暴模型的细节都跟他说了
What do you mean? You told him the details of the Firestorm Matrix?
是啊  变成火风暴可不是那么简单的
Absolutely, becoming Firestorm is a huge life change.
他要知道自己面对的是什么
He needs to know what he's getting himself into.
如果我还记得的话  向量  方差  斜边
If I remember correctly, vector, variance, hypotenuse--
质子  中子  来读哈德森大学
Proton, neutron, go H.U.!
看看  多美妙
Aw, look at that, that's so cute.
如果成功了  我们就有两个斯泰因教授了
We'll have two Professor Steins if this works.
会成功的
It's gonna work.
是啊
Yeah.
好
Okay.
当我把这个连接器放到你胸膛上
When I put this splicer on your chest
你会觉得热
you're gonna feel a rush.
那是先导分子被释放进你身体的原因
That's a molecular primer being released into your body.
接着你和斯泰因教授进行身体接触  然后
Then you can make physical contact with Professor Stein, and...
火风暴模型会帮助你们合体
Firestorm Matrix will take over.
很好
Easy enough.
准备好了吗
Ready?
现在就是最好的时机了  谢谢你  亲爱的
No time like the present. Thank you, my dear.
好吧
Okay.
再试试
Try again.
没想到会这样啊
This is unexpected.
应该要有什么反应才对吧
Something's supposed to be happening, right?
为什么没起作用
Why isn't it working?
我不知道
I don't know.
也许
Uh, well,
也许你们两个完全不匹配
looks like you two aren't compatible after all.
我还是把它拿下来吧
I'm just gonna...
所以我的努力白费了
So all this was for nothing?
相信我  现在最失望的是我
Believe me, no one is more disappointed than I am.
我看不一定
Yeah, don't be so sure about that.
下一次
Next time,
在你给别人希望之前  先把自己的工作做好吧
try to get your act together before you get someone's hopes up.
尖端科研实验室
600层
把展示会挪到下周二
Move the show-and-tell to next Tuesday,
提醒我明天打给理查德讨论股东大会的事
remind me to call Richard tomorrow about the shareholders meeting,
换掉斯诺博士的事情现在是什么进度了
and where are we with the replacement for Doctor Snow?
是应用科学楼
Applied sciences.
停下
Stop!
不许动
Don't move!
哈里森
Harrison?
韦斯特警探  谢谢你赶过来
Detective West, Thank you for coming.
麦吉博士  这是我的新搭档
Doctor McGee, this is my new partner,
斯皮沃特警探
Detective Spivot.
很高兴见到你
It's nice to meet you.
斯旺警探的牺牲让我也感到很痛心
I was saddened by Detective Thawne's passing.
请把我的慰问转达给你女儿
Please extend my condolences to your daughter.
谢谢
Thank you.
你在电话里说此事比较敏感
On the phone you mentioned this was a sensitive matter.
是的  我之所以直接联系你
It is, and I called you directly
是因为我一直很欣赏你的谨慎
because I've always appreciated your discretion in the past.
过奖了  你能告诉我是什么被盗了吗
Of course, can you tell me what was stolen?
重点不在被盗的产品  而是行窃的人
It's not so much what was stolen, but who stole it.
昨晚闯进大楼的人
The person who broke into my facility last night
是哈里森·威尔斯
was Harrison Wells.
哈里森·威尔斯已经死了
Harrison Wells is dead.
我好像记得
I seem to recall the circumstances
他如何去世的你们还没弄清
around his passing were a bit inconclusive.
有没有可能他还活着
Is there any possibility he could be alive?
不可能
Zero possibility.
我跟他相识超过二十年了
I knew the man for over 20 years.
我知道我看见了什么
I know who I saw.
唯一特别不同的就是
The only thing distinctively different was...
他又能走了
he's walking again.
我说过  我很信任你的谨慎
Like I said, I trust your discretion.
你可以在这栋楼里任意走动
You have full access to the facility.
再次感谢你  警探
Thank you again, Detective.
最开始是鲨鱼男  现在又是死人复生
First a shark-man, now a dead man walking.
我们得联系巴里  让他过来
We need to call Barry, get him in here first.
巴里不能知道
Barry can't hear about any of this.
为什么
What--why?
因为他现在已经很忙了
Because he's got a lot on his plate.
他有个重病的朋友需要照顾
He's got a friend who's sick who he needs his help,
何况哈里森·威尔斯还是杀害他母亲的凶手
and Harrison Wells is the man who murdered his mother.
一旦他听到这事
Once he hears that--
他还好吗
Is he okay?
他还好  只是
He's fine, but...
不要透露此事给包括他在内的任何人  行吗
not a word to him or anyone, okay?
好
Okay.
我只是很不会撒谎
Yeah, it's just, I'm not really good at lying.
那你最好快点学会怎么撒谎
Well, you better learn, quick.
是啊
Yeah, definitely.
中城警局
斯皮沃特  你先去吧
Spivot, go on ahead.
好的
Sure.
这是你最后一次出现在这里
This is the last time you ever show up here.
明白了吗
Do you understand?
我要再跟你谈谈
I needed to talk to you again.
我说得还不够清楚吗
How much clearer do we need to be?
爱瑞丝和我不想再看到你了
Iris and I do not want you in our lives.
你走吧
Leave, please.
回家过你自己的生活
Go home, live your life.
乔  还有一件事
Joe, there's something else.
我第一次见你的时候就想说了  可是
I wanted to tell you when I first saw you, but--
什么事
What is it?
几个月前  我变得很虚弱
Few months ago, I started getting weak.
医生给我做了一系列检查
The doctors ran a bunch of tests,
也没有查出什么结果
they couldn't figure it out.
后来结果终于出来了
But finally, they did.
我得了麦克格雷格综合症
Said I have something called MacGregor's.
大概这种病在吸过毒的人身上比较常见吧
Supposedly it's pretty common among ex-addicts.
要是运气好的话  我还能活到年底
Told me I had till the end of the year if I'm lucky.
这就是你回来找我们的原因吗
Is--is that why you came back?
我只是想让我女儿认识我
I just want my daughter to know me...
这样的我
this me.
真的很高兴你决定过来了
I'm really glad you decided to come.
我以为尖端科研实验室已经被关闭了
I thought S.T.A.R. Labs had to shut down.
被新的管理部门接管了
It's under new management.
那个跑步机是什么型号的
Whoa, what kind of treadmill is that?
宇宙级的
Cosmic.
真酷
Cool.
我们开始吧
So, let's get started.
你是不是有那种上亿美元的仪器
You got some kind of "Billion Dollar Man" technology
能治好我的膝盖
that gonna fix my knee?
其实  杰克斯  我们不是要治你的膝盖
Actually, Jax, this isn't about fixing your knee.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
粒子加速器爆炸的时候
When the Particle Accelerator exploded,
能量波以一种被称为"暗物质"的东西与你相撞
the energy wave that collided with you is known as "Dark matter."
而它不仅伤到了你的膝盖
And it didn't just hurt your knee.
它还改变了你身体的分子结构
It--it changed the molecular structure of your body.
等等  老头
Whoa, hold on, Grey.
你是说我变成了那种新闻里常提起的
So you're saying I'm like one of those meta-humans
超能力者吗
I keep hearing about on the news?
没错  请叫我教授
Yes, I am. Please, call me Professor.
我们认为你有尚未发掘出的能力
We think you have potential capabilities.
什么样的能力
What kind of capabilities?
跟斯泰因教授一样的能力
The same as Professor Stein:
你的身体可以进行分裂和融合
the ability for your body to process fission and fusion.
而且你能够将这些多余的能量
And you can harness excess energy
转化成大规模的核爆炸
and turn it into these massive nuclear blasts.
而且你还能飞
And you can fly. There's also that.
这些事你都可以做吗
So you're saying you can do all this?
只有与一位自愿与我融合的搭档
Only during times of convergence
进行融合时才能做到
with a willing partner.
融合  你和我吗
Convergence? You and me?
是的
Yes.
不行  这太疯狂了
No, this is crazy.
不  杰克斯  这是你可以
No, Jax, this is your chance
修复自身所受损伤的机会
to right the wrong that was done to you.
是  不过抱歉  你们找错人了
Yeah, sorry, you got the wrong guy.
我不想参与此事
I don't want nothing to do with this.
稍等一下
Wait a second,
我们在给你一个成为超级英雄的机会
we are giving you the chance to be a superhero,
你这么快就要拒绝吗
and you're gonna say no that quickly?
是的  我不感兴趣
Yeah, not my kind of thing.
如果这个人不想参与...
If the man isn't willing to participate--
我看过你的成绩  杰克斯
Look, I saw your test scores, Jax.
你的成绩完全可以考上大学的
Your grades were good enough to get into college,
但你没去  为什么
but you didn't go. Why?
你就是这样的人吗
Is this the type of guy you are?
遇到点小挫折就退缩了
One setback and you fold?
如果是那样  那你也不是我们想找的人
Well, then maybe you're not the guy for us anyway.
也许我不是
Well, maybe I'm not.
杰克
Jack--
也许这是注定的
Maybe this just wasn't meant to be.
凯特  别这样
Cait, come on, I mean,
杰克斯可能是我们救斯泰因教授的最后机会
Jax could be our last chance at saving Professor Stein.
他不想当超级英雄  怎么会有这样的人呢
He said no to being a superhero. Who does that?
当初你有机会的时候你并没有拒绝
I mean, you didn't say no when you had the chance.
西斯科  你会吗
Cisco, would you?
有机会获得超级能力  我报名
Chance to have superpowers? Sign me up.
我们要求杰克斯改变他的整个人生
Look, we're asking Jax to change his entire life,
牺牲他现有的东西
to sacrifice what he does have.
那并不是可以轻易就能做出的决定
I mean, that's not a decision that can be made lightly.
我也是花了很长时间
It took me a long time
才想明白做英雄这件事
to figure out this whole hero thing.
没错
Exactly,
所以我们需要愿意做这件事的人
which is why we need someone who wants to do this.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
找翰威特回来  我们必须再试一次
To get Hewitt back. We have to try again.
人类的DNA吗
Human DNA?
没错  绝对不是人形鲨鱼
Yup, definitely not a man-shark.
连鲨鱼怪也不是  女士
Not even a land shark, Ma'am.
多谢你帮我检测
Well, thanks for testing it for me.
没事  你现在打算怎么做
Yeah. What are you gonna do now?
不知道  可能会归类到"绝不会发生"文件里
I don't know, probably file it under "Never gonna happen."
反正还有别的案子
I have another case anyway.
还有什么我能帮你的吗
Oh, anything I can help you with?
没有了  警探说不用你帮忙
No, no, no, no, Detective said definitely n-not.
有什么不妥吗
Is everything all good?
没事啊  怎么了
Sure, why?
不知道
I don't know,
你表现得有点不一样
you're just acting kind of different.
没有
No! No.
我还是那个帕蒂.斯皮沃特
I'm the same old P. Spivot, you know?
事实上  我该走了
What--actually, I have to go,
很感谢你帮我检测  回见
but thank you so much for testing this, and I'll see you.
好  我...
Okay, I--
乔
Yo, Joe.
你还好吗  有什么事吗
You good? Everything all right?
挺好的  没事  我...
Yeah. No, I'm--
只是今天过得很糟糕
just had hell of a day.
怎么了
Yeah?
爱瑞丝的母亲
Iris's mother,
她告诉我她快死了
she told me she was dying.
我了解弗朗辛
Yeah, and I know Francine.
她没有骗我
She's telling the truth about this.
好吧
Okay.
爱瑞丝知道吗
Does Iris know?
还不知道
Not yet.
你找我有什么事吗
Did-- did you need something?
没什么  我只是...
Uh, no, no. I just, um...
帕蒂说你不希望我参与调查
Patty said you that you don't want me on some case
她跟你正在跟进的案子
that she's on with you.
不是
No.
我刚核实了一个线索
I was checking out a lead.
我会让你知道的
I'll let you know.
好吧
All right, cool.
你和我搭档到底怎么回事
What is up with you and my partner, anyway?
没什么  我...
Come on, I--
小巴  你的眼睛根本离不开那女孩
Bar, you can't take your eyes off that girl.
我不知道你想让我告诉你什么
I don't know what you want me to tell you.
她人很好  你知道的
I mean, she's great, you know.
她很可爱  很有趣
She's adorable and funny
我们有很多共同点  但是...
and we have a lot in common, but--
但是什么
"But, um."
我不知道  她不是爱瑞丝吧
I don't know. She's not Iris, I guess.
是啊
Right.
你十岁起就认识爱瑞丝了
You've known Iris since you were ten.
你一直都爱着她
You've been in love with her since forever.
你们俩现在是朋友
I mean, you two are friends now,
但她是你的初恋
but she was your first love.
你在别人身上永远不会找到同样的感觉
You're never gonna feel the same about anybody else,
但你不能让这阻拦你
but you can't let that stop you
发掘新恋情的脚步
from exploring something new.
是啊
Yeah.
来点欢乐的新闻  还记得闪电侠之日吗
And in happier news, remember Flash Day,
在市中心举办庆典
the downtown celebration to honor
嘉奖这位中城唯一的超级英雄
Central City's one and only superhero?
只几周的时间...
Well, just weeks--
翰威特  你得出核小体的检测结果了吗
Hewitt, you have those nucleosome results?
明天
Tomorrow.
我说过了  今晚就得要
I told you I needed them tonight.
而我告诉你了  明天会给你的
And I'm telling you you'll have them tomorrow.
我知道你觉得
You know, I know you think
自己比别人都聪明  翰威特
you're smarter than everyone here, Hewitt,
但我受够了你不干活
but I'm sick of your not doing your job,
还旷工
your not showing up.
如果你再给我惹麻烦就滚蛋
If I have any more trouble from you, you're done here.
怎么  你要把检测结果带走
What, you're gonna take the test away
然后给你别的小白鼠用吗
and give it to another lab rat of yours?
你想向董事会举报我吗
You're gonna report me to the board?
还是你在考虑解雇我
Or maybe you're thinking of firing me?
我倒想看看你能怎么样
I'd like to see you try!
现在快滚出我的实验室
Now get the hell out of my lab!
又一位超能力者袭击了艾克迈尔科技公司
被描述为"自发能量故障"的事件
What's being described as a "Spontaneous energy malfunction"
昨晚在艾克迈尔科技公司爆发了
erupted last night at Eikmeier Technologies.
科学家亨利·翰威特因此被通缉
Wanted for questioning is scientist Henry Hewitt.
当我们试图合体时  一定是触发了
Hewitt's dormant abilities must have been triggered
翰威特潜在的超能力
when we attempted the merger.
这有可能成为毁灭性的灾难
This could be catastrophic.
如果他的超能力和我一样
If his powers are anything like mine,
他就需要接地装置
he requires a grounding mechanism
来稳定他的爆炸性  否则
to stabilize his volatility. Otherwise--
没错  他的脑袋就会开花
Yeah, he's gonna pop his top,
而且据警方记录
and he's got a long history of violence,
他长期有暴力倾向
according to his police record.
警方记录
Police record?
我没看到警方记录
I didn't find a police record.
当然没有  档案是密封的
Yeah, of course not, it was sealed,
但是猜猜  我黑入了
but guess what, ya boy hacked in and--
等等  等着
hold on, wait for it.
一起殴打罪  二起故意伤人
One count battery, two counts aggravated assault,
法庭下令其进行愤怒管理治疗
court-ordered anger management therapy.
他不像是个坏人
He seemed like such a nice guy.
他还知道哈德森的书呆子歌呢
He even knew your Hudson nerd song.
你没事吧
Whoa, you okay?
显然翰威特先生的稳定性
It appears Mr. Hewitt's stability
不止是唯一的问题
isn't the only one in question.
我想我要躺下
I think I need to lie down.
我扶你去躺下
Yeah, I'll come with you.
谢谢
Thank you.
斯泰因教授的情况恶化了
Professor Stein is getting worse.
翰威特变成这样  都是因为我
And Hewitt's like this because of me.
而且因为我说过的话  杰佛逊·杰克逊
And now Jefferson Jackson will never come back
不会再回来了
because of what I said.
我只是不敢相信他能做到这地步
I just didn't believe that he has what it takes.
不是因为你不相信他
This isn't because you didn't believe in him.
有时  无限的可能性就在我们眼前
Sometimes, great possibilities are right in front of us,
而我们却看不到  因为我们选择视而不见
and we don't see them, because we choose not to.
我觉得我们应该对新事物保持开放的心态
I think that we need to be open to exploring something new.
她要死了吗
She's dying?
还剩几个月
A few months left.
我只是觉得我不能见她  老爸
I just don't think I can see her, Dad.
没关系的
And that's fine.
但是这事我们要讲清楚  爱瑞丝
But you and me need to be crystal clear about this, Iris.
如果你想和弗朗辛好好相处
If you want to have a relationship with Francine,
我没意见  你不必护着我
it's okay with me. You don't have to protect me.
我不是小孩子
I'm a grown man
这类感情我很久之前就处理过了
and I've dealt with these feelings a long time ago.
你就这样相信她了吗
So you-- you just believe her?
她过去的确做了一些不好的事
She's done some bad things in her life,
但她不会拿这种事来骗我们
but she wouldn't lie about this.
老爸  她就这样凭空出现
Dad, she shows up out of nowhere,
而且在我叫她走之后  她才说她要死了
and only says that she's dying after I told her to stay away.
她来中城不是为了我
Look, she didn't come to Central City to see me.
她是为你而来
She came because of you.
我只是想你知道一切
I just wanted you to know everything
这样你就能自己做出最好的决定
so you can make the best decision for yourself.
她始终是你妈妈
I mean, she is still your mother.
不管怎么说  不管你怎么决定  我想你知道
Either way, whatever you decide, just know,
我都会支持你
I got your back.
我知道
I know.
我猜猜
Let me guess,
你的车没问题
you don't got car troubles.
我是来道歉的  很抱歉我说了那些话
I came to apologize. I'm sorry for what I said.
没事  我接受你的道歉
It's fine. Apology accepted.
我们真的很需要你帮忙
Look, we could really use your help
拯救斯泰因教授
to save Professor Stein.
这么绝望吗
That desperate, huh?
是的
Yes.
我丈夫罗尼
My husband, Ronnie,
他以前是斯泰因教授的另一半合体
he used to be Professor Stein's other half.
其实他有份制造粒子加速器
He actually helped build the Particle Accelerator,
发生爆炸时  他也受到了影响
and when it exploded, he was affected by it too.
讽刺的是  这就是他
Ironically, that's how he got the chance
向世界展示他真正能力的机会
to show the world what he was truly capable of.
他为了保护这座城市而牺牲
And he died saving this city.
等等  他就是飞进黑洞的人
Wait, he was the guy that flew into the black hole?
就是他
That was him?
他是个英雄
He was a hero.
你也可以成为英雄
You can be one too.
我从未想过当英雄
I never wanted to be a hero.
我只想上大学
What I wanted was to go to college,
但是我家负担不起
but we couldn't afford it.
足球是我的机会  结果我连这机会也没了
Football was my way in, until that got taken from me.
我知道
I know.
我知道粒子加速器让你有所失
Look, I know the Particle Accelerator took something from you.
但同时它也赋予了你一些东西
but it also gave you something in return,
一些更加壮丽的东西
something even more spectacular,
成就更崇高事业的机会
the opportunity to be part of something bigger,
成为这个团队的一员  努力保护人们
to be part of a team that's working to protect people
让他们免受和你一样的遭遇
from losing what you lost.
我相信你注定要成为英雄
I believe you were meant to be a hero.
等一下
Whoa, hold on.
我一直都在找你  斯诺博士
I've been looking for you, Dr. Snow.
听着  我们
Hey, look, man, we're-
你把我变成了这样
You did this to me!
但你承诺的不是这样  是不是
But it's not what you promised, is it?
是不是
Is it?
快来
Come on!
去哪
Where to?
尖端科研实验室
S.T.A.R. Labs.
凯瑟琳
Caitlin.
-怎么了  -快过来
- What's wrong? - Come here.
太好了  你来了
Oh, good, you're here.
这个东西三十分钟前就耗尽了
This thing, it ran out, like, 30 minutes ago.
他的体温61度  而且还在持续上升
His temperature is 142 degrees and rising fast.
他要进入快速氧化
He's going into rapid oxidation.
我们需要冷却剂
We need to find a coolant.
我想太迟了
I think it's too late for that.
我来吧
I'll do it.
我与他合体
I'll merge with him.
你说过这是我
You said this is a chance for me
成就更崇高事业的机会
to be a part of something bigger than myself,
去帮助人们  那就是我想要的
to help people. That's what I want.
你确定吗
You're sure?
一旦合体  就无法回头了
Once you merge, there's no going back on this.
你说我会飞  是吧
And you said I could fly, right?
-没错  -好
- Damn right. - Okay.
我该怎么做
So what do I do?
我就大致说一下
Okay, well, here's the abridged version.
斯泰因教授
Professor Stein?
-斯泰因教授  -克莱丽莎  再给我五分钟
- Professor Stein? - Clarissa, five more minutes.
不  教授  你必须站起来
No, Professor, you have to get up.
杰克斯来了
Jax is here.
-嗯  -什么
- Yeah. - What?
-杰克斯来了  -什么
- Jax is here. - What?
-来  抓住我  -杰克斯
- Here, grab onto me. - Jax?
好
Yeah.
就是这样
This is it.
你回来了  杰佛逊  谢谢你
You came back, Jefferson, thank you.
就像我教练常说的
Well, like my coach always said,
走出自我  融入团队
"Out of yourself and into the team."
我要怎么做
So, how's this work?
你只需要碰一下他
Okay, all you're gonna do is touch him.
然后会怎么样
And then what happens?
你们就会变成火风暴
You become Firestorm.
好
Okay.
杰克斯
Jax?
斯泰因教授他
Is Professor Stein--
我要怎么知道
How will I know?
你好啊  杰佛逊
Hello, Jefferson.
现在你知道了
Now you know.
灰发教授做我的副驾驶员
Oh, so I get Grey as my copilot.
没人通知你有这小福利吗
Did no one ever inform you of that fringe benefit?
我们什么时候可以试飞一下
So when do we get to take this for a test spin?
不如现在吧
Uh, how about now?
看来翰威特正在充电
It looks like Hewitt's re-charging
就在中城高中橄榄球场
at Central City High School's football stadium.
等等  那就是我受伤的地方
Wait, that was where I got hurt.
西斯科  切断球场的电源
Cisco, cut the power to the field
这样他就不能再吸收能量了
so he can't draw anymore energy.
这就办  等下
I'm on it. Stand by.
翰威特  你必须停手
Hewitt! You need to stop!
这不是真正的你
This is not who you are!
斯泰因  你选了他而不是我
Stein? You chose him over me?
那是属于我的位置
That's who I'm supposed to be!
火风暴矩阵是我应得的
I deserve the Firestorm Matrix!
快走
Move, now!
冷静  杰佛逊  集中注意力
Calm down, Jefferson, focus.
用你天生的运动体质来控制
Use your natural athleticism to gain control.
你没事吧
Hey, you okay?
我是个四分卫  我知道怎么承受进攻
I was a quarterback. I know how to take a hit.
伙计们  切断电源行不通
Hey, guys, cutting the power didn't work.
仿佛我们越是激怒他  他就变得越强大
It's like the more we anger him, the stronger he gets.
就是这个  就像是那种
That's it, it's like one of those, uh,
可控聚变装置
controlled fusion devices.
火风暴漫画中的对手 亨利·翰威特的"艺名"
托卡马克
Tokamak?
对  正是
Yes, exactly,
它们聚集的能量越大
and the more powerful they become,
它们就越不稳定
the more unstable they become.
巴里  让他生气  他会烧断自己的保险丝
Barry, make him angry, and he'll blow his fuse.
想玩"猫捉老鼠"的游戏吗
You up for a little game of "Catch me if you can?"
我们上吧
Let's go for it.
好了
Okay.
翰威特  在这呢
Hey, Hewitt, over here!
呼叫翰威特博士
Paging Dr. Hewitt.
哥们  你不是很在行啊
Man, you are not good at this.
想要抱抱吗  博士
Do you need a hug, Doctor?
来啊  翰威特  使出漂亮的一击
Come on, Hewitt, give me your best shot!
就现在
Now.
你就这点本事吗  翰威特
Is that all you got, Hewitt?
伙计  难怪你没被选上
Man, no wonder you didn't make the cut
打得这么难堪
if that's how you fight.
你的第一次尝试还不错啊
Not bad for your first go at this.
我有个很棒的教练指点我
Well, I had a great coach to help me through it.
是不是  格雷
Isn't that right, Grey?
抛开我最初的观察意见
Despite my initial reservations,
我们的合作相当成功
we make a pretty fantastic team.
欢迎加入  火风暴
Welcome aboard, Firestorm.
谢谢你能来
Thank you for coming.
你不知道这对我意味着什么
You have no idea what this means to me.
我爸爸说你病了
My dad told me you were sick.
我不确定能否相信你
You know, I wasn't sure that I could believe you,
我爸爸告诉我后  我核实了一下
My dad told me so I did some checking.
事实证明你说的是真话
Turns out you're teing the truth.
这么大的事我绝对不会骗你
I would never lie to you about something so big.
真的吗
Really?
因为我真的想过在听到这个消息后
'Cause I was actually thinking that I could give you
再给你一次机会
another chance after hearing that news.
但你依然在说谎  依然藏着秘密
But you're still lying, still keeping secrets.
我是名调查记者  弗朗辛
I'm an investigative reporter, Francine.
我揭露人们试图隐瞒的事情
I uncover things that people want to keep hidden,
比如你有个儿子
like having a son.
爱瑞丝
Iris--
他是在你离开中城八个月后出生的
He was born eight months after you left Central City.
让我解释
Let me explain.
他父亲是谁  弗朗辛
Who's the father, Francine?
是我爸爸吗
Is it my dad?
我有个弟弟吗
Do I have a brother?
慢着  我不想知道  我不想知道了
Wait, you know, I don't even want--I don't want to know.
反正我没法分辨你说的是实话
I mean, I wouldn't be able to tell if you were telling the truth
还是你的又一次谎言
or if it was another one of your lies, anyway.
我想让你走
I want you to leave.
离我远点  离我父亲远点
You stay away from me, and you stay away from my father.
如果他发现自己也许有个儿子
If he finds out that he might have a son
在都不知道他的情况下长大  会击垮他的
that grew up without even knowing him, it would crush him.
请你
Just...
别来打扰我们
Leave us alone.
艾瑞斯  我...
Iris, I was--
翰威特先生怎么样了
And how is Mr. Hewitt?
貌似最后一次能量爆发把他烧倒了
Seems like that last burst of energy has burnt him out.
我们的"托卡马克"坏掉了
Our Tokamak's gone dark.
是的  我们准备把他安放到管道监狱
Yeah, we're just gonna keep him safe and sound in the pipeline
直到他决定对这一切保持沉默
till he decides to keep quiet about all this.
你准备和克莱丽莎碰面吗
So you're gonna meet up with Clarissa?
我们三天后在匹兹堡见面
We're meeting in Pittsburgh in three days.
为什么选匹兹堡
Why Pittsburgh?
我的一个同事训练我和罗纳德时功不可没
A colleague of mine was monumental in helping train Ronald and me.
她也慷慨提出要帮助咱们两个
She's graciously offered to help the two of us as well.
她怎么帮我们
How's she gonna help us?
我们的能力还有很多方面
Well, there were many aspects of our abilities
是我们没太掌握的
that we never quite achieved.
最好我们能完全领悟这一潜力
Hopefully now, we can fully realize that potential.
我最亲爱的斯诺博士
Oh, my dearest Dr. Snow.
我们也许失去了罗纳德
Ronald may be lost to us,
但我们永远不会忘记他
but he will never be forgotten.
说起来...
Speaking of...
这是罗尼的
this was Ronnie's.
他总是能用这个找到回家的路
He always used it to find his way back home.
我想把它给你
I want you to have it.
谢谢
Thank you.
这事感觉真的很诡异
You know, this whole thing is strange,
变成别人的百分之五十
being 50% of someone.
是的  但你会是个百分之百的英雄
Yeah, but you're 100% a hero.
我事先重新调试了连接器
I went ahead and recalibrated the splicer
融合现在应该更顺利了
so the merging should be even smoother now.
感谢你
Thank you.
我想说点临别赠言
If I may offer a bit of parting advice.
西斯科  我知道你很害怕
Cisco, I know you're scared,
但你的这种能力是天赋  不是诅咒
but this ability you have is a gift, not a curse.
对未知事物的恐慌是正常的
It's natural to be apprehensive about the unknown,
但看看杰佛逊
but look at Jefferson.
他迈了很大一步  让他的人生更美好
He took a leap, and it changed his life for the better.
让你和别人不一样的东西
The very thing that makes you different
也会让你与众不同
is what makes you special.
告诉你的朋友们吧
Tell your friends.
我相信是时候让好戏上路了
And now I believe it's time to take this show on the road--
或者上天  确切地说
or to the sky, if I am to be literal.
准备好了吗  杰佛逊
Are you ready, Jefferson?
好了
All right.
-待会见  -好的
- See you later. - Yeah.
那个孩子真是迈出了充满信仰的一大步
That was one hell of a leap of faith that kid took,
与斯泰因教授合为一体
merging with Professor Stein.
是啊  确实
Yeah, it was.
这或许也是你的一课
There's a lesson in there somewhere for you.
事情不总是它们看上去的样子
Things aren't always what they seem.
我们的恐惧有时会作弄我们
Our fears can play tricks on us,
让我们害怕做出改变
making us afraid to change course,
害怕继续前行
afraid to move on,
但通常躲在我们恐惧后的是
but usually, hidden behind our fears
等待我们去抓住的第二次机会
are second chances waiting to be seized...
关于人生的第二次机会
Second chances at life...
马丁·斯泰因
杰佛逊·杰克逊
关于荣誉
At glory...
关于家庭
At family...
关于爱情
At love.
这种机会不会每天出现
And these opportunities don't come around every day,
当它们出现时  我们必须勇敢起来
so when they do, we have to be brave,
把握机会  该出手时就出手
take a chance, and grab them while we can.
极速要你死
Zoom wants you dead.
我的天  原来真有
Oh, my God, it's real.
放下他
Put him down!
把你的手  你的鳍举起来
Put your hands-- your fins in the air!
你是什么人
Who the hell are you?